<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Grain to Glass on mchlrhw</title>
    <link>https://mchlrhw.github.io/blog/categories/grain-to-glass/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Grain to Glass on mchlrhw</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mchlrhw.github.io/blog/categories/grain-to-glass/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Brew 0014</title>
      <link>https://mchlrhw.github.io/blog/brewlog/brew-0014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mchlrhw.github.io/blog/brewlog/brew-0014/</guid>
      <description>Confession time: this isn&amp;rsquo;t my 14th brew, it&amp;rsquo;s my 15th, but for the sake of cataloguing brews that were drinkable I&amp;rsquo;m only going to give beers a number if they make it all the way to my glass.
My 14th, unnamed and undrinkable, brew went extremely well, up to the point that I tried to ferment it. I gave decoction another go and the yield was so good that I ended up extracting way more sugars than I needed and decided to dilute to 23 litres in order to hit the correct OG.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brew 0013</title>
      <link>https://mchlrhw.github.io/blog/brewlog/brew-0013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mchlrhw.github.io/blog/brewlog/brew-0013/</guid>
      <description>I approached this brew with both excitement and trepidation owing to the fact that I have limited temperature control for fermentation, but really wanted to try brewing my first lager.
Well, I say my first lager. My first lager was actually a pre-hopped LME kit beer that I brewed with my housemates in my second year of university. With no temperature control back then at all, and no concept of how a lager should be brewed or conditioned, we ended up with something that tasted &amp;ndash; in the words of our friend Sam &amp;ndash; like Fruit Pastels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brew 0012</title>
      <link>https://mchlrhw.github.io/blog/brewlog/brew-0012/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mchlrhw.github.io/blog/brewlog/brew-0012/</guid>
      <description>This beer has a bit of a history. It&amp;rsquo;s originally from Home Brew Beer by Greg Hughes, which I first brewed as a partial extract batch way back in 2014. It went down really well with my wife, so I brewed it again when we were expecting our first child.
It was really nice celebrating the birth (and her ability to drink again) with a cold refreshing glass of the pink stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>