<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mchlrhw</title>
    <link>https://mchlrhw.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on mchlrhw</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mchlrhw.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mutually Recursive Prime Functions</title>
      <link>https://mchlrhw.github.io/blog/posts/mutually-recursive-prime-functions-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mchlrhw.github.io/blog/posts/mutually-recursive-prime-functions-3/</guid>
      <description>In the previous two posts I covered recursion, mutual recursion, primality testing and prime generation. In this post we&amp;rsquo;ll close the loop (or maybe that should be loops) by making all of the functions we&amp;rsquo;ve covered so far interdependent, so that no matter which one we call there&amp;rsquo;s always a chance that all of them will find there way onto the call stack.
Everything Depends on Something
What a shame primes_to is only ever called if we call it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brew 0014</title>
      <link>https://mchlrhw.github.io/blog/brewlog/brew-0014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mchlrhw.github.io/blog/brewlog/brew-0014/</guid>
      <description>Confession time: this isn&amp;rsquo;t my 14th brew, it&amp;rsquo;s my 15th, but for the sake of cataloguing brews that were drinkable I&amp;rsquo;m only going to give beers a number if they make it all the way to my glass.
My 14th, unnamed and undrinkable, brew went extremely well, up to the point that I tried to ferment it. I gave decoction another go and the yield was so good that I ended up extracting way more sugars than I needed and decided to dilute to 23 litres in order to hit the correct OG.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mutually Recursive Prime Functions</title>
      <link>https://mchlrhw.github.io/blog/posts/mutually-recursive-prime-functions-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mchlrhw.github.io/blog/posts/mutually-recursive-prime-functions-2/</guid>
      <description>In the previous post I talked about what recursion is, what it takes for a number to be prime, and how we can apply recursion to the problem of primality testing and prime factorisation. In this post we&amp;rsquo;ll take the next logical step: finding primes in a sea of integers.
Hunting for Primes
So, after the work we did in the previous post, we now have two functions that depend on each other to work at all; but we can do better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mutually Recursive Prime Functions</title>
      <link>https://mchlrhw.github.io/blog/posts/mutually-recursive-prime-functions-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mchlrhw.github.io/blog/posts/mutually-recursive-prime-functions-1/</guid>
      <description>OK, I admit it&amp;hellip; I love prime numbers. I don&amp;rsquo;t know why, but I know I&amp;rsquo;m not alone. There&amp;rsquo;s just something about them. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s their indivisible nature &amp;ndash; their atomicity &amp;ndash; that seems so appealing. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s the fact that they&amp;rsquo;re well understood, but nevertheless intangible &amp;ndash; there&amp;rsquo;s no equation for finding primes and most of our methods for finding them involve brute-force. Anyway, whatever it is, I just love them and I love writing code to generate them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brew 0013</title>
      <link>https://mchlrhw.github.io/blog/brewlog/brew-0013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mchlrhw.github.io/blog/brewlog/brew-0013/</guid>
      <description>I approached this brew with both excitement and trepidation owing to the fact that I have limited temperature control for fermentation, but really wanted to try brewing my first lager.
Well, I say my first lager. My first lager was actually a pre-hopped LME kit beer that I brewed with my housemates in my second year of university. With no temperature control back then at all, and no concept of how a lager should be brewed or conditioned, we ended up with something that tasted &amp;ndash; in the words of our friend Sam &amp;ndash; like Fruit Pastels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Post</title>
      <link>https://mchlrhw.github.io/blog/posts/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 13:27:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mchlrhw.github.io/blog/posts/first-post/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s give this blogging thing a go&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brew 0012</title>
      <link>https://mchlrhw.github.io/blog/brewlog/brew-0012/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mchlrhw.github.io/blog/brewlog/brew-0012/</guid>
      <description>This beer has a bit of a history. It&amp;rsquo;s originally from Home Brew Beer by Greg Hughes, which I first brewed as a partial extract batch way back in 2014. It went down really well with my wife, so I brewed it again when we were expecting our first child.
It was really nice celebrating the birth (and her ability to drink again) with a cold refreshing glass of the pink stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>